

☐ +1 551-263-9462 • ☑ yzhang31@wpi.edu

# **Summary**

Ph.D. candidate in Data Science, with strong deep learning background and programming skills and the ability to work independently or as part of a research team. Broad research interests include:

o deep learning

o meta-learning

o reinforcement learning

o imitation Learning

o spatial-temporal data mining

o big data analysis

## Education

Worcester Polytechnic Institute (WPI)Worcester, MAPh.D. Candidate in Data Science. GPA 4.0/4.0Expected 2022Stevens Institute of TechnologyHoboken, NJM.S in Financial Engineering (Data Science Track). GPA 3.98/4.02016-2018Shanghai Jiao Tong UniversityShanghai, ChinaB.E in Computer Science2012-2016

# Research & Work Experience

### Worcester Polytechnic Institute, Laboratory of Prof. Yanhua Li

Worcester, MA Aug 2018-Present

Research Assistant

Funded by National Science Foundation

- Combined the meta reinforcement learning with meta imitation learning to enable learning of new behaviours (in progress).
- Proposed a Continuous Spatial-Temporal Meta-Learning algorithm (cST-ML) which employed variational inference and deep neural networks to better capture the temporal uncertainties of time series data.
- o Proposed a novel generative adversarial networks equipped with dynamic convolutional layer and self-attention mechanism to solve the spatial-temporal estimation problem.
- Designed a novel generative adversarial networks to better capture the spatial patterns of spatial-temporal data.

## Worcester Polytechnic Institute, Data Science Research Group

Worcester, MA

Research Member

Aug 2018-Present

- Supervised research projects of graduate students on human mobility estimation with conditional generative adversarial networks.
- Assisted other research members in solving research issues related to deep learning and large-scale data analytics.

#### **Stevens Institute of Technology**

Hoboken, NJ

Teaching Assistant

Aug 2017-May 2018

o Assisted in teaching graduate courses including Data Mining and Database Management.

## **Technical Skills**

- **Programming:** Python, R, C/C++, Java
- o Frameworks: PyTorch, TensorFlow, scikit-learn, NumPy, SciPy
- o Others: L⁴TEX, Matlab, SQL

### **Publications**

- [KDD] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou, Xiangnan Kong and Jun Luo. Curb-GAN: Conditional Urban Traffic Estimation through Spatio-Temporal Generative Adversarial Networks. In Proceedings of the 26th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD '20).
- o [ICDM] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou and Jun Luo. cST-ML: Continuous Spatial-Temporal Meta-Learning for Traffic Dynamics Prediction. 2020 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM).

- o [ICDM] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou, Xiangnan Kong and Jun Luo. TrafficGAN: Off-Deployment Traffic Estimation with Traffic Generative Adversarial Networks. 2019 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM).
- [TBD] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou, Xiangnan Kong and Jun Luo. Off-Deployment Traffic Estimation
   A Traffic Generative Adversarial Networks Approach. In IEEE Transactions on Big Data.
- o [[SIGSPATIAL GIS'20]] Han Bao, Xun Zhou, Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Yiqun Xie. COVID-GAN: Estimating Human Mobility Responses to COVID-19 Pandemic through Spatio-Temporal Conditional Generative Adversarial Networks.In Proceedings of the 28th ACM SIGSPATIAL International Conference on Advances in Geographic Information Systems.

# **Conference & Presentation Experience**

26th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD '20)	Virtual Event
Conference Presentor	Aug 2020
2019 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM) Conference Presentor	Beijing, China <i>Nov</i> 2019
Graduate Research Innovation Exchange (GRIE) Poster Presentor	Worcester, MA Feb 2019
A 1	

### **Awards**

Graduate Fellowship by National Science Foundation 2018-Present Scholarship for international students from Stevens Institute of Technology 2016-2018